[
  {"question": "amor", "response": "odio"},
  {"question": "feliz", "response": "triste"},
  {"question": "rico", "response": "pobre"},
  {"question": "día", "response": "noche"},
  {"question": "caliente", "response": "frío"},
  {"question": "rápido", "response": "lento"},
  {"question": "bueno", "response": "malo"},
  {"question": "alto", "response": "bajo"},
  {"question": "claro", "response": "oscuro"},
  {"question": "viejo", "response": "joven"},
  {"question": "fácil", "response": "difícil"},
  {"question": "fuerte", "response": "débil"},
  {"question": "grande", "response": "pequeño"},
  {"question": "primavera", "response": "invierno"},
  {"question": "norte", "response": "sur"},
  {"question": "ruido", "response": "silencio"},
  {"question": "luz", "response": "oscuridad"},
  {"question": "largo", "response": "corto"},
  {"question": "abundante", "response": "escaso"},
  {"question": "valiente", "response": "cobarde"},
  {"question": "nuevo", "response": "viejo"},
  {"question": "joven", "response": "anciano"},
  {"question": "seco", "response": "húmedo"},
  {"question": "interesante", "response": "aburrido"},
  {"question": "moderno", "response": "antiguo"},
  {"question": "duro", "response": "blando"},
  {"question": "sencillo", "response": "complicado"},
  {"question": "positivo", "response": "negativo"},
  {"question": "activo", "response": "inactivo"},
  {"question": "generoso", "response": "egoísta"},
  {"question": "amable", "response": "grosero"},
  {"question": "completo", "response": "incompleto"},
  {"question": "rápido", "response": "despacio"},
  {"question": "delgado", "response": "gordo"},
  {"question": "simple", "response": "complicado"},
  {"question": "mejor", "response": "peor"},
  {"question": "lindo", "response": "feo"},
  {"question": "directo", "response": "indirecto"},
  {"question": "valioso", "response": "insignificante"},
  {"question": "amplio", "response": "estrecho"},
  {"question": "sucio", "response": "limpio"},
  {"question": "visible", "response": "invisible"},
  {"question": "rico", "response": "pobre"},
  {"question": "superior", "response": "inferior"},
  {"question": "raro", "response": "común"},
  {"question": "simpático", "response": "antipático"},
  {"question": "dulce", "response": "amargo"},
  {"question": "inteligente", "response": "tonto"},
  {"question": "firme", "response": "débil"},
  {"question": "profundo", "response": "superficial"},
  {"question": "amistoso", "response": "hostil"},
  {"question": "horizontal", "response": "vertical"}
]